Eating fruits and vegetables is
a part of healthy balanced diet,
and during pregnancy its more important as
they provide you with many essential nutrients,
vitamins and minerals that are necessary
for the normal growth, and development of
the fetus. But some fruits and vegetables are
a big NO! as they can be very harmful for the
Mother and its baby. So without any furthur adue
lets move on, and have a look over each item.
Number 1: Papaya
Papaya is a fruit that has the highest potential
of causing abortion in pregnant women, but you
dont have to worry too much as the chemical that
is responsible for it is present in very least
amount in fresh ripe papaya fruit, but still you
have to be very careful and its best to avoid it,
for good. Unripe and semi ripe papaya fruit
have the highest quantity of papain, Thats
right papain is the real culprit, when consumed
it causes uterine contractions and bleeding which
then leads to miscarriage and abortion. So its
best to avoid and stay away from this fruit.
ok lets move on.
Number 2: Pineapples
Not as abortifacient as papaya but still, you
might have to say goodbye to this sweet-sour
delight. Atleast for the first 3 months of
pregnancy. Now this fruit consists of bromalien,
which causes uterine contractions which results
in miscarriage or abortion. Now on this,
many researches have mixed views.
Some say that its good to eat and
some advice to refrain from it.
But again, its best to avoid,
as taking precautions is much better,
because you never know what might happen.
Number 3: Green Potatoes
Yes, you heard it right, now there is nothing
wrong with potatoes, but the green colored
spots on them is a poision, thats right a POISION!
thats not only harmful for you but also for your
child. Studies have shown that those green colored
spots are glycoalkaloid solanin. And this solanin
has teratogenic effects on the embryo,
which means that when consumed in high
amounts or even one toxic dose of this poision can
cause deformations in the embryo. Not only this,
but it also causes uterine bleeding which
can result in miscarriage. But you dont
have to worry as long as the potatoes
you consume are free from green spots.
So those were some dangerous
fruits to avoid during pregnancy,
Takecare of yourself and goodbye!